# Paulo John Fernandez

Cebu, Central Visayas, Philippines

fernandezpaulojohn@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/paulo-john-fernandez



+639772001950



https://github.com/fernandezpaulojohn? tab=repositories

## **Summary**

BS-IT Student in AMA University and Ambitious to be a Software Engineer/ Developer harnessing and studying programming languages in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Typescript, C#, Flutter, Dart Python and PHP. ALso have experience using frameworks in Reactjs, ViteJS, NextJS, Asp.net, Blazor, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React Native.

More than eight years as an IT Service Desk/Helpdesk Analyst/ Service Administrator (Windows and Linux) and more than three years in Customer Service for Business Process Outsourcing companies and more than 5 years working as a Online Freelancer/ GVA.

I have served huge companies such as Johnsons and Johnsons, RioTinto, and Comcast.

The following are the tools I have experience with:

#### Ticketing Systems:

- Service Now
- ServiceDesk Plus
- Freshdesk
- FreshService
- Zendesk
- Solarwinds
- JIRA

#### Remote Control Tools:

- LogMeIn
- ConnectWise
- BeyondTrust
- Teamviewer
- Quick Assist

#### VPN:

- Pulse Secure
- Sonic Wall
- Forticlient
- Orange
- Compass-ERA
- Global Protect
- Global VPN

#### Other Relevant Tools:

- · Active Directory
- SCCM

- Citrix
- Amazon Workspace
- Microsoft Office 365
- Microsoft Teams
- Skype for Business
- Exchange Admin Center
- OneDrive Admin Center
- Azure
- Intune
- Sentinel One Management Console
- 1Password
- Mimecast
- Powershell (basic)
- Nuclino
- CrowdStrike

Should you find my experience relevant to your demands, I am looking forward to new opportunities and challenges.

Please check my digital portfolio below for more information about my work.

https://dashboard.freeeup.com/profiles/details/-?

ga=2.92659677.1772014378.1681562804-1747731285.1642487608

https://paulojohnfernandez.wixsite.com/pj-portfolio

https://www.onlinejobs.ph/jobseekers/info/712536

https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/~01b261fbaa0962fbb4/

https://talent.hubstaff.com/profiles/paulo-john-d-fernandez

# **Experience**

#### Support Specialist

Stockhouse Publishing Ltd.

Dec 2022 - Present (10 months)

- Moderate and monitored users in the Stockhouse Forums
- Remove posts, escalate issues, and maintain users to follow forum policy.

# ZOX Customer service, Order Processing and Fulfillment.

ZOX

May 2020 - Jan 2023 (2 years 9 months)

- Respond to Customer Queries via Gorgias
- Process orders through Shopify
- Conduct fulfillment using desktop shopper

# Virtua Assistant, Shopify Customer Support, SMM, Lead Generation and SEO prospect list at FreeUp

FreeUp

Apr 2020 - Dec 2022 (2 years 9 months)

# lead Generation, SMM, Customer support and SEO prospect list

FreeUp

Feb 2020 - Dec 2022 (2 years 11 months)

#### Lead Generation and Outreach For Facebook and Linkedin.

#### Re/Max Hometown

Apr 2020 - Aug 2022 (2 years 5 months)

- Connect with agents in Facebook group and do outreach.
- Connect with agents on Linkedin and do outreach.
- Send the initial script to agents.
- Send follow up for agents.
- Input agents to Google sheets.
- Submit End of the day report.

# Lead Generation and Outreach For Facebook and Linkedin.

#### Justin Mcrae Ventures

Apr 2020 - Aug 2022 (2 years 5 months)

- Connect with agents in Facebook group and do outreach.
- Connect with agents on Linkedin and do outreach.
- Send the initial script to agents.
- Send follow up for agents.
- Input agents to Google sheets.
- Submit End of the day report.

# Freelance - Customer Support

#### Bookblock

Jan 2022 - May 2022 (5 months)

- Respond to Customer Queries via Freshdesk
- Process orders through Woocomerce
- Conduct fulfillment using ILG

# Lead Generation and Outreach For LinkedIn.

#### The Daily Client Machine

Nov 2020 - Feb 2021 (4 months)

- Connect with prospective clients on Linkedin and do outreach.
- Send the initial script to clients.
- Send follow up for clients.
- Input clients to Google sheets.
- Submit End of the day report.

# Lead Generation/Prospecting and Outreach For Linkedin.

#### **UNCMN.CO.NZ**

Sep 2020 - Oct 2020 (2 months)

- Connect with agents on Linkedin and do outreach.
- Send the initial script to agents.

- Send follow up for agents.
- Input agents to Google sheets.

# M Lead Generation and Outreach For Facebook and LinkedIn.

#### Melton Real Estate | Key Realty

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020 (2 months)

- Connect with agents in the Facebook group and do outreach.
- Connect with agents on Linkedin and do outreach.
- Send the initial script to agents.
- Send follow up for agents.
- Input agents to Google sheets.
- Submit End of the day report.

## Customer service, Order Processing and Fulfillment.

#### **Fitpacks**

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020 (3 months)

- Respond to Customer Queries via Gmail.
- Process orders through Shopify
- Conduct fulfillment using desktop shopper

### Lead Generation and Outreach Via Linkedin Sales Navigator

#### The Marketing Agency

Dec 2019 - Apr 2020 (5 months)

- Connect with prospects via Linkedin Sales Navigator
- Send Initial Scripts
- Records data via Google sheets

# Virtual Assistant, Social Media Customer Support, QA Gamer Beta tester and live Support

Upwork

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020 (7 months)

# Customer Support Officer

**QBE** Insurance

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year)

Analyze cases given by the underwriters and process the request as per product being provided by tye underwriters

# IT Helpdesk Technical Support

#### Accenture

Nov 2016 - Jul 2018 (1 year 9 months)

- Process technical Issues Such as Citrix Servers
- Adding and Removing member in Active Directory

- Adding and Removing member in Active Mailbox using PowerShell
- Process Symantec Token
- Process Mobile Iron
- Office365 Support
- Microsoft Lync Server Support
- Conduct Remote Desktop Support
- Outbound and Inbound Calls
- Reports for the process of tickets End of the Day

## Teller/Service Associate

**East West Banking Corporation** 

Aug 2015 - Nov 2015 (4 months)

Company: EastWest Bank

Position: Teller/Service Associate (August2015 – November 2015)

- · Processing and releasing of clients Deposited Money
- · Processing of End of the Day cheques

# 附 Operation Admin Assistant

**SM Supermalls** 

May 2014 - Dec 2014 (8 months)

Company: SM Prime Holdings

Position: Operations Assistant/Mall Admin

(May 15, 2014 - December 20, 2014)

- · In-charge of processing working permits
- Handles I.D. Orientation
- · Assists in setting up exhibits
- Supervise billings of tenants, security posting, and Bio Augmentation via S.A.P. system
- Responsible for enrollment of new applicants through Finger tech (Biometrics)

#### **Student**

University of San Carlos

Jun 2009 - Oct 2013 (4 years 5 months)

#### **Education**

#### Informatics Education Ltd.

Bachelor of Science - Web Development, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design

2018 - 2018

Focus on Web Design and Development front end.

# **University of San Carlos**

Bachelor's degree, Human Resources Management and Services 2009 - 2013

#### **AMA** University

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology Oct 2021 - Present

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Google Cloud Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Coursera
  X4W8QNCEYS5W
- Technical Support Fundamentals Coursera 688534S7R44K
- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking Coursera
  TPM3CEWCKYVL
- Operating Systems and You: Becoming a Power User Coursera V2MXYHBL8NS4
- System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services Coursera S49LGLBGPUV2
- Google IT Support Certificate Credly by Pearson KRXZSYFHHGFW
- Google IT Support Specialization Coursera KRXZSYFHHGFW
- IT Security: Defense against the digital dark arts Coursera
- Getting started with Microsoft Office 365 Coursera 7MYNKXURDHCU
- Getting Started with Microsoft OneNote Coursera
  YQBFW4Q7BPCB
- Managing Security in Google Cloud Coursera
  ST5M75CEBVL9
- Introduction to Microsoft Azure Cloud Services Coursera SH8424L57WKC

- Microsoft Azure Management Tools and Security Solutions Coursera 93JNYXF4R99X Microsoft Azure Services and Lifecycles - Coursera M964HLVT3EZC Hardware Security - Coursera UFTH489363XE Software Security - Coursera 2M8H6XYTGRX8 **Cryptography** - Coursera 3ZFGCGFBBGBV **Usable Security** - Coursera KQ88DQCEP97C Get Connected English 0222 CGA - Cisco NDG Linux Unhatched English 0222b cga - Cisco Networking Academy Super VA Virtual Assistant Team Certificate - Virtual Assistant Team AWS - Cybsersecuurity Trends and Certifications for Developers - Edukasyon.ph Cebu Game Dev November Meetup - Cebu Game Dev **CCNA: Introduction to Networks** - Cisco Partner: CPA - Programming Essentials in C++ - Cisco
- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence AMA University

Partner: CPP - Advanced Programming in C++ - Cisco

"React: Why you should and How?" - Gordon College

- Google Ads Training Inspired Filipino Freelancers
- React Better Code Reviews The Company Cebu
- CCNAv7: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials AMA University
- CCNA: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials Cisco

#### **Skills**

Logistics Management • Order Fulfillment • Order Processing • Research Skills • Microsoft Office • Data Analysis • Microsoft PowerPoint • Microsoft Word • HTML • C (Programming Language)